hello my name is Cuba libres Kyle and I
am the founding member of We the People
which is going to be the probably free
name it's by all of us the global
cooperative it's going to solve all of
our world's problems so this is the
intro I'm gonna walk you through on why
we need one why we need a solution at
all what that solution is in my opinion
how we implement that solution what that
looks like to co-create together who's
involved in the whole project where the
project will be taking place which is a
bit of a throwaway question but I wanted
to answer all of them and it's when it's
happening into the phases and what it
looks like now versus what its gonna
look like in the utopian future no if I
did that the one phase it walks you
through some phases and then the bigger
why why would I just talked about is the
solution why it's better than what we
currently have why it solves so many of
the issues that capitalism has and then
I will also wrap that up with a ending
segment on how you get involved and how
you get in contact with me thank you
hello Internet welcome to the first
video which will all be spliced together
why why we need to change anything I
think this one's a little bit of a
no-brainer this one is if you've been
paying attention to the world at all
we're not doing so great
globally there is way too much war and
all of the issues with that all of the
side effects masculine migration of
destroyed infrastructure in cities of
all the untapped human potential that
we're literally destroying there is the
climate change which is destroying our
planet the ecosystem we rely on we all
need to breathe air we all need to drink
water we share those systems and we are
destroying them
we have manmade climate change that is
wreaking havoc there's more tropical
storms more earthquakes even
like there's a ridiculous number of
things going on it feels like the earth
might be mad at us for a good reason
there is a resource crisis in nearly
every resort our fisheries our forestry
our food systems with topsoil with all
of the mining and gas and energy we have
a resource crisis because we're not
designed our world is designed for a
very select few people and it's designed
to make them money not to keep our
planet alive and not to increase
happiness for the vast majority of us on
this planet there's the personal why
that personally I think we're stressed
out
we and we are stressed by the state of
the world and our lives our lives are
designed to create more stress and just
deal with it
we're isolated we have to deal with
everything on our own and it's too much
we feel isolated me feel lonely we feel
anxious and depressed and I think we're
seeing that in a lot of health issues
with my generation I'm sure the next one
even going before happening way earlier
in our lives the personal stress of
stress stress in general not a big fan
the world works for only this tiny
fraction of humanity and we can do
better by tapping in if we tap into a
fraction of the human potential on this
planet we can solve all of the world's
problems from like the mundane personal
problems to these like catastrophic
global ones rather easily we just need
the system in place and we can have fun
while we do it it can be fun to save the
world do you give your best self to tap
into what you have to give the people
that are gonna do that it's its own
reward and so that's why we need a
better world we need a world that's sane
that's run for all of us and so we're
gonna create it and I will be talking to
the next video which will be all spliced
together on what exactly weird
I mean what are we creating that's a
good question
thanks for asking we were creating the
system people to have the conversations
to be able to collaborate on a scale we
have never collaborated on the floor to
be able to be efficient and not keep
reinventing the wheel at every different
city and every different community we
can build on what came before and own it
together so we create the platform the
Facebook that's for the people by the
people designed to be a project
management system to find groups that
are meaningful to you to monitor
projects that have already been made and
to do all of this amazing to botan on
things and just stay up-to-date on the
topics that are important to you it's
the dashboard for everything else
it's the dashboard for your life and
we're going to make it together with
that in place and before it's in place
we're all it's going to run some of them
offline to learn what this really needs
to look like we are going to build
projects and so those projects look like
taking back our knowledge of politicians
and sharing what their voting record is
organize the information in a usable way
taking back our economics by sharing
data on corporations that's already
available but organizing it so we can
know without marketing what's best for
us what's healthiest for us what we like
what is least corrupt we can create a
world that makes sense
just ensure your knowledge we can share
connection we can make up where we
individually lack and what other people
individually lack by creating technology
that does that we are gonna there's an
infinite number of projects I'll make
our lives better and we're building on
the people that came before cuz we're
owning it together which gets to the
next circle which is all of this is
co-owned Cohn cooperated by the global
cooperative that we everyone's invited
to and the global cooperative we get to
create things together we get to
purchase things that already create it
as it makes sense financially and we
vote on it we get to the odd time people
will gift us stuff because they don't
longer want their project it's it
doesn't have the threshold it's better
to be run here then there they will gift
it to us but that's not what I'm
counting on I'm counting on that we make
I'm together to make more sense and we
purchase them as it makes financial
sense to do so
but this global cooperative exists in
the bigger world and it's gonna start
small and it's gonna grow out more I
believe where it's going to eventually
take over it'll eventually be what
capitalism currently is and we will own
everything together and our world will
be much more sane and based on actual
laws of physics and not based on the
emotions of the person in power at that
at that moment in time we get to share
knowledge and share it in the ownership
and running of this operative that is
what we are creating all of it platform
all of the projects and the global
cooperative itself and we're designing
it so that everyone can give their own
unique piece how do we create this
together one of the big questions is how
we fund it it's a pretty important
question in our current society and
although there are different ways to
fund it at different stages and phases
which is the same thing um there are the
main idea is that there is a membership
fee of $10 per month and that enables
our members to be able to vote on things
to discuss stuff to be as involved as
they want to be and the beauty is that
the $10 is pooled together if you have a
million members and that's ten million
dollars a month that we get to vote on
what to do with that money right it's
Netflix for social change you're
subscribing to be a part of the solution
you're so membership dues of $10 per
month which is low enough that it
shouldn't be a barrier to people but
it's still that you have to want to be a
part of this you have to want to create
a better world together and to cooperate
and the $10 a month is enough the
barrier that like we're probably not
gonna get as many trolls as he wants to
pay $10 a month to come in to annoy
people some people probably will figure
we have created the platform to be able
to have the conversation that was what
the what was what was in the last video
and with the platform were able to
create project so what that looks like
is more of a contest so we create the
technology
allows us to have the conversations on a
massive scale so a million people having
a conversation can be difficult as I
learned in the Occupy movement it was
really it was beautiful I loved it there
was so much about it that I loved but I
didn't like was the inefficiency of the
meetings and I don't even know how they
would run them better in that in that
state that it was they had to a day I
was like okay well how do we wrap how do
we have anything in less than a
five-hour conversation when you want
everyone's voice heard and you want to
be able to vote on stuff and move things
forward and there's trade-offs with that
but with technology I don't think we
need to have this many trade-offs we can
have win-win situations where people are
able to be in smaller groups to have
their voice heard and we're able to vote
up the things they're most important so
the more people the more important an
idea is an issue that someone's arising
where people are like oh yeah I feel
that way too
then those things are floated to the top
they get to the top through throughout
the rhythms and people don't and we walk
through a project management system with
the timeline so you can't have an
eight-hour conversation on a name it's
like you generate ideas people vote on
which ones are the best the top three
come out and then everyone votes on the
top three and the winner is the name
then you move forward with the next
thing right like there was there was a
process to it where if you come in at
this point you don't get to go back and
read I hate to say oh not then don't be
part of it like everything that was
doing before has been done and you might
be able to get involved in the next
iteration right there's enough people
like I don't like the name I don't like
the name it can you can trigger a new
vote after the project's all done right
ten years on a year on six months on
whatever the timeline is to go back and
relook at this project and we also this
is part of the howl though I don't
because I don't know which other video
to put it in that the culture of us
creating together it has to be fun has
to be its own reward that if people are
paying to contribute pain to be part of
this it needs to be a place where people
belong and that doesn't mean everyone
belongs everywhere because we're not
those people it means that everyone can
have a place and find it and we create
the algorithms that allow them to do
that where when
you work really well with a certain
person you're more likely to be to be
matched up with them if you have a group
you work amazing with you can pick that
group every time and I'm already be in
it and where you were maybe like me and
you maybe find it hard to find a group
and that's an awkward ceiling in
situation it can put you in one and as
you give feedback and other people give
you feedback on what works and what
doesn't it's able to better find a group
for you that works and the groups
working together everyone's voices get
her the best ideas get filtered and
unfiltered as the word I was leave for
more than floating filtered up to the
top by people voting on though not
everyone votes on everything everyone
everyone gets to vote on what they feel
is important so you can put what's
important to you if you want to vote on
everything you're going to spend your
life on on this platform right if you
want to vote on just the important
things then you don't vote on anything
else just the ones that everyone else
said everyone should vote on are the
ones you vote on it anything in between
is available to you so because we've
created the system we don't have the
trade offs we can have a democracy on
nearly everything with people having
contribution where they want to have it
and where it doesn't work we
troubleshoot it we figure it out we
don't throw it out because a piece of it
doesn't work we figure out what will
work if this doesn't work to create a
system it turns out the crowd is a
horrible people to create a project with
then we do it in smaller groups but
transparently we have like Kodi groups
deciding how to how to create this and
the best option gets funded and people
vote on that there's so many there's a
million different iterations for this it
isn't about what that one won't work
might not we're gonna figure it out the
whole point is we're putting the system
in place to have the conversation so
when troubles arise we can fix it way
more easily than the current system does
because the people who you have to
convince that it's a solution are
involved into creating the solution and
you don't have to convince them there's
so much beauty as to like why this is a
solution that I will get into on the
last video but that is the how we have
created the platform to have the
conversations that enable us to work
through the projects and keep them going
the different people who are way better
at this stuff than I am are gonna have
even better ideas that's the whole point
we want people we want to enable people
to be the best their best selves and
find their place
and we're gonna create the technology
that's gonna do that who is invited and
everyone everyone is invited we need
space for 7.5 billion people and growing
if they want to come everyone is invited
there needs to be space for everyone
that being said we do not need 7.5
billion people to make this work need a
fraction of that you consider 1 percent
of the people on this planet currently
own all the money and all the power we
can have 1 percent of people who truly
unlocked their cooperative self that
they want to because when cooperative
people get together it benefits everyone
the whole point is instead of one person
pushing everyone else down to get to the
top and this person like pulls this
person dance like ok one person is on
the top that's one person is happy and
everyone else who's not because they got
the gold they got this the highest point
and even the second place is the first
loser first is a cooperative system
where you're helping each other out to
see everyone can get to the top right
and so which means you're pulling them
up you're helping them up you're
inviting them up and in a world that
even a tiny fraction of people are doing
this it's helping everyone and this one
looks more inspiring to most people than
this one so this one is is
understandably we fight against it and
we don't feel like there's some people
who really want to be at the top and
people strive to be there most of us
don't feel this is a fair system so we
create a cooperative one and the
co-operative one is going to out-compete
the competitive one I believe it at my
core and I have so much evidence to that
which I'll get into a bit of it in the
why but the who is simultaneously
everyone's invited and yet we need a
tiny fraction of that for every position
for every everyone's a puzzle piece with
their own unique contribution there is
you were not in competition with anyone
cuz nobody is you and yet there's
nothing that you have no characteristic
whether physical mental spiritual that
sets you apart from everyone right every
no matter what the characteristic is
somebody else has it right but it's the
unique combination of characteristics
that makes you unique and so for every
piece that we need a puzzle piece to
fill there's multiple puzzle pieces
fill that but for every puzzle piece you
can find a spot so it's it's that's the
hip it's we're unlocking true human
potential so we're finding spaces for
everyone we're with the power of
technology we're helping people find
their space it's not something that
comes easily to everyone it's one of
life's missions and we don't write like
why am I here Who am I where do I fit
who loves me how do I feel seeing you
know how do i we're gonna we're gonna
maybe not fix that because it's still a
lot of internal work but we're gonna
make that so much easier for people that
all of the hurdles and blocks that stop
us individually are going to be moved
aside by people who can see how to move
that aside right what's hard for you is
easy for me and vice versa so we're
gonna make it easy for everyone and in
doing so we're gonna untapped human
potential which is gonna make it so much
easier to solve every complex problem on
this planet because there's someone who
has the solution they just don't have
the voice they just don't have the
personality to get it out there we're
creating the system where they don't
need to have that so I think I got into
a bunch of other answers to other
questions but that in a nutshell is
who's invited everyone and how I mean
how we create the system to work
together as we create it to work
together where it's a little bit weird
for this project and projects but the
idea is I mean since eventually ideally
we're owning everything the where is
everywhere but in the beginning its
online because online is a lot easier to
have an added person without it having a
lot of added cost right if somebody
comes on and they don't have money to
pay $10 a month and we still want to
have scholarships for them so that they
can still come on board and offer their
their opinions and offer then we can do
that because it's not costing us $10 a
month to add someone right that the
threshold sorry the finance to add a new
person is very low online online also is
where the technology and tools are that
help us balance the unusual trade-offs
so online is the main answer but also
there's this idea of probably if I can
get into it you know why the last why
that part of the beauty of creating this
way is it thresholds have to be met
before you're taking a risk so and
that's going to be a more
a rule later on in the beginning is the
beginning we can create with hundred
people you're not gonna have if you
create a food out for a hundred people
if everyone put in divided the cost by a
hundred it would be astronomical
but the idea is you're crowdfunding and
creating something that more people
would use there's 100 it's designed for
the hundred people that extrapolates the
population but for a lot of things the
threshold has to be met first so you're
saying okay well we're not going to
co-create a food app until we have a
million people on board or we're not
going to co-create a Vancouver based
food AB something that helps Vancouver
people share food and have less waste
and do until a certain percentage of
Vancouverites have signed up or in the
case of angular because it is so big
it's actually a concrete number right
like once 10,000 people sign up you're
walking through the system that helps
your 10,000 people eat better and so
there's thresholds to be made for the
local if you're starting a makerspace or
a cooperative lab if you just want to
fund it with a thousand people and
everyone puts in $1,000 you cost a
million dollars cool you have it you
don't need to have our threshold made
but if you're looking for community
funds to pay for it we're gonna have
those things in place where you have to
get 10,000 people signed up or you have
to get a million people signed up but
whatever happens to be or a percentage
of your population because if you're a
tiny town of a thousand people it
doesn't make sense for you to need to
get 10,000 people right but but we have
the metrics and the where is
simultaneous um nowhere and everywhere
right like in the individual people one
global food system isn't going to work
having global food having systems that
are local and then having them connected
in a way where when someone doesn't have
enough food or you want to trade that
those systems are in place so
simultaneously the where is you know
we're online and everywhere all right
when we do these things what is the time
line and I see this unfolding in phases
right now this phase is me trying to
communicate this idea and grow
membership to a point where I would
trust having a democracy and so to me I
feel like 100 members is a good starting
point for like we can name it we can
decide on our vision and values we can
pick a first project figure out how to
crowd fund it and even if we have to get
together and we probably will have to
get together
person to create it we're doing it with
the understanding that it makes the next
project easier in the next project
easier and then once we get a couple of
projects under our belt and we know how
to do it we create the platform the beta
that allows us to have the conversations
online and then we improve that system
with a few projects once we have that
platform in place we're and our
membership has grown enough that there's
enough money to fund multiple projects
so we're funding one at a time with this
pool of money and then it's like oh yeah
but the money is growing faster than
we're spending it by like threefold
right then oh look we could maybe a fund
a second project also in our membership
grows it's gonna unlock more like you
have a million people working on a
project and a tiny fraction of them
wanted be super involved in their space
for them great but as you unlock more
people people want to want to be as
involved as they want to be right as you
have more people than work for them you
can unlock simultaneous projects right
if you are breaking this down into into
piecemeal and there's way more pieces of
work to do than people we need to grow
people and as there's way more people
than pieces to do we want to unlock more
projects so there's an organic growth to
it that bit fell as long as when we get
to the phase where we have the platform
at least the beta in place and we've run
and we've unlocked simultaneous projects
so we have more than one going at a time
once we even get to two projects
especially three projects that's when we
go from the funding model of 10 dollars
per project to 10 dollars per month
because then when you're running
multiple projects you have all of this
pool of money and you can have more
niche based projects that people want to
work on because you can find one of the
three and eventually we unlock unlimited
projects where anyone can start one
people vote on whether it gets funded
but anyone can start one expression of
yourself one unit and so that's a bit of
the the phases and timeline a little
hard to explain in video or easy to
explain I got a piece of paper with a
pen and paper concentric circles but the
timeline on the phases and where we're
going
right now the last Y which is supposed
to wrap it all up but I could talk about
this again for several hours so we'll
see how much I can get in in like a 10
minute son
I believe that when we co-create
together on a system based on
cooperation instead of competition it
solves so much of the issues that
capitalism has caused and I don't even
know how to convey all of that but I
want to start with a parable of sorts
which I realize is supposed to be in the
Bible but I can't make up the word
that's anyway it's not a Bible story but
if you have two groups of people for
some reason I've decided they're both
10,000 people they both get $100,000
reward for getting to the top but they
have different motivating factors so the
first group is just whoever gets to the
top first gets the million dollars so
there's gonna be so much incentive to
cheat to get to push other people down
or to work together in small groups and
then split it but you're still not
concerned that you want it out compete
everyone else you want to be the first
for the first tiny group to get up to
the top of the mountain and that's
you're gonna be your solo focus just
like get to the top it is efficient way
as possible everybody else right
the others team of 10,000 people same
million-dollar prize but their goal is
to get everybody to the top of it to the
top of the mountain that group is what
is 10,000 they each get $100 that's not
really incentive enough to like it's
almost too much of an incentive yeah
bless when I did it was ten thousand ten
thousand sperm gets a dollar but they're
going to be trying to find a way to help
the slowest and weakest amongst them get
to the top because they all have to get
to the top to get that get that million
dollar prize and in order for that to
happen they're going to be more
cooperative they're going to since it's
not as much of an incentive right you're
not necessarily going to push people
down for $100 you're not gonna like you
can't find you're out of yours because
we don't want to have to carry you to
the top it might happen hundred all is a
still an incentive but it's more about
you're gonna be enjoying the journey
you're gonna be
looking around see you nature enjoying
the people you're with figuring out
together how to best best get yourselves
to the top of the mountain so it's it's
better on all fronts and of course if I
felt the opposite way I'm sure I could
think of a of a metaphor the other way
around right that shows competition but
the point is competition isn't bad in
and of itself but the incentive means
we're pushing other people down and
we're just trying to stop other people
from getting to where we are and
definitely surpassing us whereas
innovation on this side we all get to
benefit from it when someone has an idea
that will work we can be like oh yeah
and implement it and push it forward and
that is pretty much a nutshell what the
why of why we want to be cooperative
instead of competitive and the truth is
we're still competing in a competitive
system we're still in the greater
capitalist global system and if we don't
out-compete them we weren't kind of
meant to be like when something goes
wrong we have all of us to troubleshoot
oh shoot it all of us to implement it if
we can't out-compete the competitors and
within that system we weren't supposed
to be here
we're losing we're lost but I don't
think that's the case I think compa
cooperation oates competes competition
hands down because here you have one
person even if it's the gold medal
mountain climber yeah they're gonna get
to the top first before this group but
the mountain climbers have you having to
get everyone to the top having the same
rule these people are gonna get there
they're gonna have more fun along the
way everyone's gonna get to win and so
it's not one winner 9 9999 losers the
other big piece of the why I'm creating
this is or we are creating it I'm just a
catalyst is that the solutions that are
offered right now I see is like kind of
falling into two camps both of which
aren't great one of which is that we
devolve into chaos and then like from
revolution or we like from the ashes we
will rise and I don't want to get to
ashes I don't want my world to burn down
I don't want the chaos and violence that
comes from revolution in that way I want
peace I don't like
it's live in peace I want every person
on this planet to live in peace so I
would like to not have chaos and
Armageddon just personally the other
issue is people take the system as a
whole and try to tinker with it so try
to fix like this just this tiny part but
since it's all interconnected like you
can't really solve war without solving
poverty you can't solve climate change
without solving poverty like it's all
interconnected and the tinkerine just
doesn't work we need to recreate the
system the system is so inefficient and
unfair that like transferring a little
bit of wealth to the porridge doesn't
work we need to like revamp the entire
systems what we're doing is we're
building the scaffolding under the
current system which is working in a way
right there's food in the supermarket's
the roads mostly don't have potholes
like it's like we're getting places
things are happening and innovation is
happening we don't bring that down to
zero because that's chaos people starve
people die and a big piece so that
that's a big piece of the whys if this
is an actual systemic solution that's
designed to win it's designed for
competition for cooperation to
out-compete competition because it's
designed to have the conversation design
that anyone who sees a problem if it's a
big enough problem we agree on it can
implement a solution or can just point
it out and other people can invent a
solution that we empower the individual
and that's a big piece of the why that
we are empowering the individual we're
giving like 99.9 percent of the people
on this planet their best life possible
or 99.9 percent of their best life
possible and that's huge cuz that
unlocks human potential we aren't
stressed by the day-to-day living of
life we get to unlock who we truly are
are we artists are we engineers and it's
gonna be different for everybody it's
not about being carbon copies of each
other that's why we're not in
competition naturally we're in it we can
be in cooperation because there's no
competition for being me I'm the only me
there is and I need to find my space and
we're going to help do that through
technology one of the other things
besides the mountain that I wanted the
mountain analogy is the that we are
creating for purpose not for profit
whereas corporations have to do the
exact opposite no matter what sector
they're in corporations have to maximize
profit for their shareholders legally so
if they have a decision to make to make
their product better versus therefore
their purpose better right their thing
that they're in the market for and to
make profit they have to make profit now
a lot of making the profit means making
this better but only to a point only to
the point that keeps people coming back
that it's eventually gonna break down
that it's right like they're not
designing for purpose so health care is
designed to make money not to keep
people healthy and not to make people
healthy so if proper nutrition is going
to help society be healthy there's no
incentive it not because that's gonna
hurt profit and not maximum it ends yeah
it's gonna hurt profit so who cares
about the purpose whereas we're gonna
flip that we're going to innovate for
profit for purpose we're gonna say okay
there's 10,000 was having a conversation
about how we how we eat what stops us
from eating well how do we create a
better system of food then we're making
decisions for purpose now we can't
ignore profit we still need to be in the
world especially right now with finance
and access to resources and access to
people who have the best innovation and
the most talent and that comes at a cost
currently so we need to be financially
stable it's it's financially sustainable
so we have to take finance into account
but when it comes to what are we gonna
make another dollar or are we going to
make another whatever the equivalent is
the dollar value in purpose we pick
purpose so that is is a huge thing so
when we design it together I believe
that we design much more efficiently
we're much more efficient with our
resources because we have the incentive
to make things cheaper and truly cheaper
to just make it with less resources and
make it with with less human involvement
right to automate but we all get to get
the benefit of that not just a tiny
fraction at the top who gets to to get
all of all of that profit there's less
risk involved in creating together
because there's more eyes to see
problems more more brains to like think
about solutions and more hands to
implement it like we're just we're
better together and so I do believe in
this newer
system we will have more innovation but
even if the competition is it like 100
and this is 85 75 % it still up competes
this because like this is one person or
one tiny group of people and assuming
this purple in this group or like 75% of
smart 75% is efficient and innovative
there's more of them working together so
it like it exponentially grows and where
I'm not right on that I'm wrong we will
find the issues we will troubleshoot
them together because we designed the
system to do it together and so that's
the big buy and I did it in under 10
minutes that's my wife sandwich so we'll
do one more video at the end to wrap it
all up and say how you get involved okay
alright so if you watched that entire 30
minute video and you want to be involved
I probably want you involved so please
email me at collaborative democracy at
gmail.com it'll be written in the
description below as well as I might add
a few other ways for you to contact me
right now that's the best way to contact
me because I do have a Facebook group I
can add you to but I don't want people
randomly asking to join because I have
to either know you in real life or
connect with you through this Facebook
video and feel confident that you are a
real person who's looking to do good in
the world so please email me tell me who
you are what spoke to you in this video
and why you want to be here and then
let's fix the we're all together Thanks